Guide to the Records of the Leake and Watts Children's Home 1802-1983 (bulk 1831-1949) MS 377
New-York Historical Society
- Series III - Society for the Aid of Friendless Women and Children / Hopewell Society of Brooklyn, 1869-1947
  - Subseries III.1 - Minutes, 1876-1947
    - Minutes of the Board of Managers, 1935-1947 (Offsite-box LW-41, Volume 281)
    - Minutes of the Summerland Board of Trustees, 1926-1942 (Offsite-box LW-41, Volume 282)
  - Subseries III.2 - Reports, 1869-1942
    The subseries consists of published annual reports of the Society for the Aid of Friendless Women and Children/Hopewell Society of Brooklyn 1883-1945 (not inclusive), followed by annual reports of their Summerland facility and one bound volume of SAFWC annual reports. The subseries concludes with four bound volumes of handwritten reports of the Matron, the Nursery Committee, and the Investigative Committee 1869-1892.
    Inspection reports are in subseries III.4.
    - SAFWC Annual Reports, 1883-1885 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 1)
    - SAFWC Annual Reports, 1892-1893 and 1895-1897 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 2)
    - SAFWC Annual Reports, 1900-1902 and 1905-1909 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 3)
    - SAFWC Annual Reports, 1909-1915 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 4)
    - SAFWC Annual Reports, 1917-1920 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 5)
    - Hopewell Annual Reports, 1921, 1922, 1925, 1926, 1929, 1933, 1937 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 6)
    - Hopewell Annual Reports, 1941, 1945 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 7)
    - SAFWC Summerland Annual Reports, 1906, 1919 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 8)
    - Hopewell-Summerland Annual Reports, 1935-1936 and 1941-1942 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 9)
    - SAFWC Annual Reports, 1886-1904 (Offsite-box LW-41, Volume 283)
    - Reports of the Matron, 1869-1916 (Offsite-box LW-41, Volume 284)
    - Reports of the Nursery Committee, 1871-1897 (Offsite-box LW-42, Volume 285)
    - Reports of the Investigative Committee, 1874-1883 (Offsite-box LW-42, Volume 286)
    - Reports of the Investigating Committee, 1888-1892 (Offsite-box LW-42, Volume 287)
  - Subseries III.3 - Records of Women and Children, 1869-1946
    The subseries consists of 23 bound volumes and two folders of records regarding people served by the Society for the Aid of Friendless Women and Children/Hopewell Society of Brooklyn, including registers, admission and discharge records and medical records. Volumes are listed first, followed by folders.
    - Register [oversize], 1869-1878 (Offsite-box LW-59, Volume 288)
    - Register [oversize], 1879-1886 (Offsite-box LW-60, Volume 289)
    - Chronological/Narrative Register of Adult Admissions and Discharges, 1877-1882 (Offsite-box LW-42, Volume 290)
    - Children's Admissions and Discharges, 1878-1898 (Offsite-box LW-42, Volume 291)
    - Children's Admissions and Discharges, 1903-1908 (Offsite-box LW-42, Volume 292)
    - Children's Admissions and Discharges, 1904-1918 (Offsite-box LW-42, Volume 293)
    - Children's Admissions and Discharges, 1906-1914 (Offsite-box LW-42, Volume 294)
    - [SAFWC] Children's Admissions, circa 1905-1911 (Offsite-box LW-43, Volume 295)
    - Children's Admissions and Discharges, 1908-1914 (Offsite-box LW-43, Volume 296)
    - Children's Admissions and Discharges and Monthly Movement of Population Reports to State Board of Charities, 1914-1921 (Offsite-box LW-43, Volume 297)
    - SAFWC/Hopewell Children's Records, 1918-1922 (Offsite-box LW-43, Volume 298)
    - Hopewell Society Register [oversize], circa 1921-1946 (Offsite-box LW-60, Volume 299)
    - Children's Admissions and Discharges, 1922-1925 (Offsite-box LW-43, Volume 300)
    - Children's Admissions and Discharges, 1925-1930 (Offsite-box LW-43, Volume 301)
    - Children's Admissions and Discharges, 1930-1936 (Offsite-box LW-43, Volume 302)
    - Children's Admissions and Discharges, 1936-1940 (Offsite-box LW-43, Volume 303)
    - Children's Admissions and Discharges, 1941-1946 (Offsite-box LW-43, Volume 304)
    - Case Numbers, 1943-1946 (Offsite-box LW-44, Volume 305)
    - Admissions and Discharges - City Cases, 1900-1919 (Offsite-box LW-44, Volume 306)
    - Admissions and Discharges - City Cases, 1911-1934 (Offsite-box LW-44, Volume 307)
    - Admissions and Discharges - City Cases, 1934-1946 (Offsite-box LW-44, Volume 308)
    - Children's Medical Records, 1915-1923 (Offsite-box LW-44, Volume 309)
    - Children's Medical Records, 1924-1946 (Offsite-box LW-44, Volume 310)
    - SAFWC Children's Record Book (partial, disbound), 1898-1903 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 10)
    - SAFWC/Hopewell Children's Records, 1910, 1936-1939 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 11)
  - Subseries III.4 - Financial and Administrative Records, 1860-1957 (bulk 1860-1946)
    The subseries consists of 20 bound ledgers and other financial volumes and 1.5 boxes of financial and other administrative records of the Society for the Aid of Friendless Women and Children/Hopewell Society. Volumes are arranged first, followed by loose materials.
    - Treasurer's Cash Accounts, 1860-1891 (Offsite-box LW-44, Volume 311)
    - Treasurer's Cash Accounts, 1891-1902 (Offsite-box LW-44, Volume 312)
    - Treasurer's Cash Accounts, 1902-1912 (Offsite-box LW-45, Volume 313)
    - Treasurer's Cash Accounts, 1912-1922 (Offsite-box LW-45, Volume 314)
    - Cash Accounts, 1913-1914 (Offsite-box LW-45, Volume 315)
    - Treasurer's Accounts, 1922-1933 (Offsite-box LW-45, Volume 316)
    - Treasurer's Accounts, 1934-1938 (Offsite-box LW-45, Volume 317)
    - Treasurer's Accounts, 1939-1942 (Offsite-box LW-45, Volume 318)
    - Treasurer's Accounts, 1943-1945 (Offsite-box LW-45, Volume 319)
    - Summerland Journal, 1918-1936 (Offsite-box LW-45, Volume 320)
    - Summerland Accounts, 1936-1943 (Offsite-box LW-46, Volume 321)
    - Cash Journal, 1931-1937 (Offsite-box LW-46, Volume 322)
    - City Bills and Clara Boyer Fund, 1941 and 1945 (Offsite-box LW-46, Volume 323)
    - Clara Boyer Fund and 75th Anniversary Fund, circa 1944 (Offsite-box LW-46, Volume 324)
    - Payroll Book, 1943-1946 (Offsite-box LW-46, Volume 325)
    - Ledger, 1945 (Offsite-box LW-46, Volume 326)
    - Journal/Cash Book, 1946 (Offsite-box LW-46, Volume 327)
    - Petty Cash, 1946 (Offsite-box LW-46, Volume 328)
    - Check Stubs, 1946 January-May (Offsite-box LW-46, Volume 329)
    - Check Stubs, 1946 May-August (Offsite-box LW-46, Volume 330)
    - Change of Name Certified Copy and Other Copies, 1921 and circa 1930-1939 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 12)
    - Hopewell Summerland and Sevilla-Hopewell Summerland Misc. Legal and Financial Records, circa 1920-1948 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 13)
    - Hopewell - Blueprints, Building Permits, circa 1928-1935 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 1)
    - Hopewell Inspection Reports, 1929-1936 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 2)
    - Hopewell Inspection Reports, 1936-1940 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 3)
    - Hopewell Real Estate and Financial, 1939-1942 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 4)
    - Hopewell Ida Harris Purdy Auxiliary Meetings Program, 1941 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 5)
    - Hopewell Annex Division Population Reports, 1942 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 6)
    - Hopewell Tax Documents, 1942-1946 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 7)
    - Hopewell Bank Statements, Cancelled Checks, Ration Slips, 1943-1946 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 8)
    - Hopewell Financial Reports, 1944-1945 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 9)
    - Hopewell Society General Ledger, 1946 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 10)
    - Hopewell Paid Bills A-F, 1946 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 1)
    - Hopewell Paid Bills G-M, 1946 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 2)
    - Hopewell Paid Bills N-S, 1946 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 3)
    - Hopewell Paid Bills T-Z, 1946 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 4)
    - Hopewell Miscellaneous, 1939-1957 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 5)
- Series IV - Sevilla Home for Children, 1889-1947
  The series consists of six bound volumes of minutes, one other volume, and one half box of records of the Sevilla Home for Children. Volumes are arranged first, followed by other materials.
  - Minutes, 1889-1904 (Offsite-box LW-46, Volume 331)
  - Minutes, 1905-1914 (Offsite-box LW-46, Volume 332)
  - Minutes, 1914-1920 (Offsite-box LW-47, Volume 333)
  - Minutes, 1920-1935 (Offsite-box LW-47, Volume 334)
  - Minutes, 1935-1946 (Offsite-box LW-47, Volume 335)
  - Minutes, 1946-1947 (Offsite-box LW-47, Volume 336)
  - Steam and Electric Plant Specifications and Plans, circa 1946 (Offsite-box LW-47, Volume 337)
  - Sevilla Home: "From the Will of Jose Sevilla", undated (Offsite-box 32, Folder 6)
  - Sevilla Home Blueprints and Specifications, 1906 and undated (Offsite-box 32, Folder 7)
  - Sevilla Home Inspections (Dept. of Social Welfare), 1940, 1945 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 8)
  - Sevilla Home W-2 Forms, circa 1942-1946 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 9)
  - Sevilla Home Insurance Report of Injury Forms, 1945-1946 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 10)
  - Sevilla Home Financial Report, 1946 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 11)
  - Sevilla Home Correspondence, 1947 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 12)
- Series V - Sevilla-Hopewell Society, 1946-1949
  The series contains 3 volumes, including 1 volume of minutes, and 1 additional box of materials, containing primarily financial documents along with a small number of reports and legal documents.
  - Minutes, 1947-1949 (Offsite-box LW-48, Volume 338)
  - Journal, Disbursements, Insurance, 1947-1948 (Offsite-box LW-49, Volume 339)
  - Children's Accounts, 1947 (Offsite-box LW-49, Volume 340)
  - Financial Statements, Reports to Trustees, 1946-1947 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 1)
  - IRS, 1947-1948 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 2)
  - Merger of Sevilla and Hopewell, and By-Laws, 1947-1949 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 3)
  - Consolidation of Leake and Watts and Sevilla-Hopewell, 1947-1948 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 4)
  - City Bank Farmers Trust Invested Income Account Statements, 1948-1949 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 5)
  - Certificate No. 64 and Supporting Documents (accounts payable), 1948 July (Offsite-box 33, Folder 6)
  - Certificate No. 65 and Supporting Documents (accounts payable), 1948 August (Offsite-box 33, Folder 7)
  - Certificates 66, 67, and 69, 1948 August-September (Offsite-box 33, Folder 8)
  - Certificate No. 70 and Supporting Documents (accounts payable), 1948 September (Offsite-box 33, Folder 9)
  - Certificates 71-73 and Supporting Documents (accounts payable), 1948 September-October (Offsite-box 33, Folder 10)
  - Certificates 74-75 and Supporting Documents (accounts payable), 1948 November (Offsite-box 33, Folder 11)
  - Certificates 76-77 and Supporting Documents (accounts payable), 1948 December (Offsite-box 33, Folder 12)
  - Certificates 78-80 and Supporting Documents (accounts payable), 1949 January-February (Offsite-box 33, Folder 13)
  - Certificate 82 and Supporting Documents (accounts payable), 1949 March (Offsite-box 33, Folder 14)
- Series VI - Masonville (N.Y.), 1802-1865
  The series consists of 10 volumes of handwritten rent, letter and account books, 1817-1865, relating to land in Masonville, Delaware County, New York originally owned by Rev. John Mason Knox, who also servced circa 1860's as Leake and Watts' treasurer. The series also contains one published volume of memoirs of John M. Mason.
  - Rent Book, 1802-1817 (Offsite-box LW-48, Volume 341)
  - Rent Book, 1817-1838 (Offsite-box LW-49, Volume 342)
  - Accounts, 1819-1836 (Offsite-box LW-48, Volume 343)
  - Rent Book, circa 1833-1850 (Offsite-box LW-48, Volume 344)
  - Memoranda and Correspondence, 1837-1842 (Offsite-box LW-48, Volume 345)
  - Accounts, 1837-1844 (Offsite-box LW-48, Volume 346)
  - Correspondence, 1839-1842 (Offsite-box LW-48, Volume 347)
  - Rent Book, circa 1839-1864 (Offsite-box LW-48, Volume 348)
  - Receipts, 1847-1850 (Offsite-box LW-48, Volume 349)
  - Receipts, 1855-1865 (Offsite-box LW-48, Volume 350)
  - Memoirs of John M. Mason, DD., S.T.P., with Portions of His Correspondence compiled by Jacob Van Vechten, New York: Robert Carter and Brothers, 1856, with an inscription by John Knox 1856 (Offsite-box LW-48, Volume 351)
- Series VII - Bibles, Colored Orphan Asylum, volume from unidentified agency, circa 1894-1898, undated
  The series consists of 3 bibles and 1 other volume, each of which may have belonged to any of the organizations whose records are assembled in this collection. No owners are inscribed on the volumes. The series also consists of the constitution of the Colored Orphan Asylum. This document is part of this collection for unknown reasons.
  - Constitution of the Association for the Benefit of Colored Orphans, undated (Offsite-box 25, Folder 11)
  - Bible, undated (Offsite-box LW-61, Volume 352)
  - Bible, undated (Offsite-box LW-63, Volume 353)
  - Bible, undated (Offsite-box LW-62, Volume 354)
  - Brokerage Insurance Alliance Volume, circa 1894-1898 (Volume 355)